FLEX X COP 2
CHARACTERS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS,
AND EVENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE FICTITIOUS
ALL CHILD ACTORS AND ANIMALS
FILMED IN A SAFE ENVIRONMENT
THE LATE JEONG MINJAE
Why did you do that?
Minjae isn't even a detective anymore.
Why?
He's not a cop!
My poor Minjae. What am I going to do?
[sobbing] Minjae.
[wails] Minjae!
Minjae!
-[voice shaking] I'm sorry.
-Minjae!
I'm so sorry.
GANGHA JUNGANG HOSPITAL FUNERAL HALL
Ah. I'll catch up with you later.
Okay.
EPISODE 13
THE LITTLE PRINCE
[Seongwon] Don't run away from this.
Once you accept it,
you'll finally be free.
After all, you're my Little Prince.
THE LITTLE PRINCE
I HAD TO DRAW THE INSIDE
OF THE BOA CONSTRICTOR
YOU ALWAYS HAVE
TO EXPLAIN EVERYTHING TO GROWN-UPS
[Seongwon] The moment I first met you
is one of them.
Me?
At the gathering?
You don't remember, do you?
We met way before that.
When I was just a kid.
I've liked you ever since then.
Back then,
you were a lot quieter than you are now.
You were shorter and thinner.
The hallway was bright,
and a breeze was
coming in through the window.
SEO YUKYUNG PSYCHIATRIC CLINIC
[Seongwon] How's my drawing?
It's really good.
Do you know what this is?
It's a puppy.
[Seongwon] My picture.
Everyone said it was weird.
You were the only person
who complimented me.
[Dr. Seo] Jin Isoo.
Come inside.
KEEP QUIET
Yu Seongwon.
Do you remember him?
Yu Seongwon?
Did he kill someone?
What makes you think that?
Because he was
captivated by death as a child.
He first came to my clinic
when he was nine years old.
SEO YUKYUNG PSYCHIATRIC CLINIC
Him.
Can you make him normal?
I think he's insane.
Move.
Out of my way!
-[screams]
-Mom, what do you think you're doing?
Jackie is dead.
JACKIE
You know, don't you?
Did Jackie bite you?
He always does.
Apparently, he thinks he's above me.
I see.
You must've resented Jackie.
After Jackie died,
how did you feel?
It was nice.
He doesn't bark or bite me anymore.
He listens to me now.
Can you draw Jackie for me?
He never once drew a dog that was alive.
Still, he got better
with art therapy and counseling,
and nothing happened for a while,
but it flared up again
after the chairman passed away.
He saw the dead body
and was inspired.
What's going on?
Your son has locked the door.
Yu Seongwon!
[yelling] Yu Seongwon!
-[knocking on door]
-Open the door.
[yelling] Yu Seongwon, open the door!
What do you think?
The title is "Marionette."
[softly] Crazy bastard.
Do you like it?
Get this crazy bastard out of here.
Stop it! Let go!
No, seriously!
Stop it!
Let go of me!
Nothing...
happened here.
If this gets out,
this hospital is finished.
We'll be careful, ma'am.
Take this off! [exclaims, screams]
Take it off!
[Dr. Seo] In the end, he was
hospitalized for a very long time.
[Dr. Seo] I helped Seongwon
channel his fantasies about death
into works of art.
I heard he became a famous artist.
What exactly did he do?
He's been involved in six cases so far.
Two were his models.
He's killing people to create his pieces.
It looks like
my treatment failed after all.
You know Seongwon likes you, don't you?
He said you alone understood him.
What is his weakness?
Please help me.
His weakness?
There was one final piece he made
while he was hospitalized.
It was also of a dog.
Jackie's collar was wrapped around it.
Then, even now,
he must have the victims' belongings.
To relive the thrill of his killings,
I'm sure that somewhere,
he would have displayed
his victims' belongings.
Like works of art.
JO NAYEONG, CHOI YEONGMIN,
KIM HEEJUN, JEONG MINJAE
YU SEONGWON
UBS CHAIRWOMAN'S SON, FAMOUS SCULPTOR
The day before she went missing,
Jo Nayeong went
to Yu Seongwon's studio in his car.
On the 12th, he dropped her off at CONEX.
She was last seen
on camera in the corridor.
But there's no footage
of her leaving CONEX.
[Junyoung] Choi Yeongmin said
he had his modeling job on the eighth.
The next morning, on the ninth,
he drove his car from the studio,
parked it, then disappeared.
And Kim Heejun said he was
going to meet Yu Seongwon.
[Kyungjin] But he left his car
at Deoksan-ri and disappeared.
Lastly, Jeong Minjae,
who was following Yu Seongwon...
[Kyungjin] His car was found
near the Hangang River.
They all follow a similar pattern.
The victims were all with Yu Seongwon,
then the next day, in a crowded place,
or somewhere too far out
for the camera to make out their face,
they left their car and vanished.
Then when and how did he kill them?
Did Yu Seongwon lure them
into meeting him again somewhere else?
But for the days the victims went missing,
Yu Seongwon has a solid alibi.
JEONG MINJAE DETECTIVE AGENCY
CEO JEONG MINJAE
SHADOW WITHOUT A TRACE
TRACK TO THE END
-[mouse clicks]
-[sighs heavily]
YU SEONGWON
JEONG MINJAE
VEHICLE STOP LOCATION
65, EUNDAM-RO 13BEON-GIL, GANGHA-GU
ALL NOTES
SONG AREUM
65, EUNDAM-RO 13BEON-GIL, GANGHA-GU
-Hey, you're here.
-Did you see all the files?
Yeah.
But all the victims were still alive
the day after they met Yu Seongwon.
We can't figure out
when and how he killed them.
Our theory is...
that this person is Yu Seongwon.
The victims were probably killed
on the day they met Yu Seongwon.
He wanted to leave proof
they were alive the next day,
so Yu Seongwon went out himself.
He put on their clothes to look like them,
went to a crowded place,
and then disappeared.
That's why these were classified
as missing-person cases.
Yeah, that makes more sense.
[softly] Wow!
He's one scary guy, that Yu Seongwon.
-[Areum] Yu Seongwon?
No, he didn't come here.
Ah, I see.
Are there security cameras
in this building?
There's one on the first floor,
but it's broken.
I kept asking them to fix it,
but they never did.
Why do you ask?
My colleague,
who was following Yu Seongwon,
died.
I think he was kidnapped around here.
[Areum] Oh, my God.
Was Yu Seongwon behind it?
That's very likely.
Come to think of it, that day,
just after I'd arrived home,
I heard something strange.
If this is Yu Seongwon,
who drove this car?
I don't know who it is,
but it means he has an accomplice.
I know who the accomplice is.
This is...
[Hyera] Yes.
The man who's always
by Yu Seongwon's side, right?
That man lives with him in the studio,
so I figured he would know something.
But he was an accomplice.
Do you know who he is?
Not really. He's just called "Mr. Hwang."
He's looked after the Yu family's villa
since Seongwon was a child.
His studio used to be their villa.
Whatever Yu Seongwon says,
that man obeys.
Hey, Hwang. Bring me some more chocolate.
Hey, aren't you being a bit too rude?
Don't call him "Hwang."
But I don't know his name.
It's fine. He's my servant.
His father was also
a servant to my family.
But he messed up big time and almost died,
then my dad saved him.
That's why he's my servant.
Right, Hwang?
Yes, Young Master.
First, let's check UBS's employee list.
Okay.
-Check who's registered at the studio.
-Got it.
Are you okay?
I'm just going to focus
on catching Yu Seongwon for now.
Right, let's do that.
UBS EMPLOYEE LIST
REGISTERED RESIDENTS RECORD
-Did you find him?
He's not here. Not in the employee list,
or at the address.
Let's just bring him in for questioning.
If he gets out after that, he might run.
Should I go talk to him?
I don't know if that's the right approach.
If he's completely on Yu Seongwon's side,
it might backfire on us.
We need a reason to make a move.
The inside of the car
has been wiped clean.
-Sir.
-What is it?
Yes, sir.
Right. Please send it over right away.
We found a fingerprint
on Jeong Minjae's car.
NAME, HWANG JONGSU
CRIMINAL RECORD, 4 PRIORS
Hwang Jongsu, age 59.
[Isoo] He's a former gang member
with priors for drugs and fatal assault.
Let's go bring him in.
-[Junyoung] Okay.
-[Kyungjin] Okay.
DETECTIVE DIVISION
1 DAY EARLIER
Do you know where Police Chief Hwang is?
Yes, he's in prison.
That's not someone else's problem.
It could happen to you, too.
Even if you lived
an honest life in public service,
I can make that happen to you.
But I doubt you were that honest.
Leave my son alone.
Keep me updated on the investigation.
DETECTIVE DIVISION
VIOLENT CRIME INVESTIGATION
TEAM 1, TEAM 2
Yes, sir.
[Taegyun] So, how did it go?
Fingerprint? You found a fingerprint?
Yes, sir. Team 1 has identified him.
His name is Hwang Jongsu.
Right, okay.
FINGERPRINT SEARCH RESULTS
NAME, HWANG JONGSU
-Hello?
-[Taegyun] Hello, ma'am?
I don't think you need to worry anymore.
We have a suspect now.
His name is Hwang Jongsu.
He has a criminal record.
JEONG TAESEON
MR. HWANG HAS BEEN FLAGGED
[Seongwon] Have you finished eating?
Yes, I've finished. [clearing throat]
[gulps] Yes.
I heard you owe my dad big time.
Yes.
He saved my life.
[Seongwon] Mmm.
I heard that before he died,
he told you to protect me no matter what.
Yes, that's right.
Now's that time.
Time to repay what you owe.
Run for your life.
Make sure...
you don't get caught.
-[engine revs]
-[tires screech]
Hey, turn the car around.
Hwang Jongsu.
-[engine revving]
-[tires screech]
Hwang Jongsu, stop the car!
Mr. Hwang! Stop the car!
-[tires screech]
-[metallic crunch]
-[Isoo grunts]
-[tires screeching]
-[all grunt]
-[Isoo panting]
-[engine revving]
-[tires screeching]
-Follow him.
-[Kyungjin] Yes, ma'am.
He's not here.
-That way.
-Right.
[Mr. Hwang, panting] Ma'am, it's me.
Where are you?
The Myeongun-dong construction site.
[Taeseon] That's not far.
-Wait there.
-Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Hwang!
Young Master.
Can we
please talk?
Please go ahead.
We got a suicidal person.
Myeongun-dong construction site. Hurry.
We're not here
to arrest you.
I've done a lot of bad things in my life.
I deserve to die.
Mr. Hwang Jongsu.
You care about Yu Seongwon, right?
I do.
As much as my own life.
Before the chairman passed away,
he made me promise.
Then we need to stop him
from killing more people.
That's...
not something we can stop.
First,
just come this way.
Come talk with me.
[Mr. Hwang] Young Master.
The chairman said to me
that I should let Seongwon
do whatever he wants.
If I can't, I should die.
Please come tell me...
what you mean by that.
Huh?
Even if I told you,
you wouldn't understand.
Mr. Hwang.
-[indistinct murmuring]
-[camera shutters clicking]
-[Junyoung] Stop filming!
-[Kyungjin] Stop filming!
-[Junyoung] I said, stop filming!
-[Kyungjin] Stop!
No filming. Cameras down.
-Police! No filming!
-[Junyoung] Cameras down!
[Kyungjin] Get down from there!
No filming!
Lower your cameras.
-[Junyoung] Cameras down!
-[Kyungjin] Lower your cameras!
-Stop filming.
-[Junyoung] No filming.
-Cameras down!
-[Kyungjin] Lower your cameras!
They're here.
[Junyoung] Lower your cameras!
-Stop filming.
-[heavy thud, squelch]
-[reporters gasps]
-[reporter 1] What's that?
-[swears softly]
-[camera shutters clicking]
[Kyungjin] Stop filming!
No filming! Your cameras!
Turn off your cameras!
You can't film this!
-[reporter 2] Why?
-Stop filming!
-Hello? I'm at...
The suicidal person just...
Yes, Myeongun-dong.
Please could you hurry?
[Kyungjin] Lower your cameras!
You can't film this.
Turn off your cameras!
-Turn off your cameras!
-[breath trembling]
[Kyungjin] Lower your cameras!
Stop filming!
Stop filming! You can't film this!
Mmm.
CHASING THE TRUTH OF THAT DAY
SPECIAL REPORT
ON JIN ISOO'S MURDER ALLEGATIONS
I stand before you again
after a long absence.
Given the gravity of the case,
I will personally lead
today's special broadcast.
Last night, a man fell from a building
at a deserted construction site.
To understand the full scope of this case,
we must begin
with the murder of Kim Younghwan.
Ten days ago, Mr. Kim Younghwan,
the CEO of a film production company,
was brutally murdered.
The prime suspect was
the victim's close friend
and the only person present at the scene,
Detective Jin Isoo.
There was compelling evidence,
but Detective Jin was released
without charge a few days later.
[Mujin] I thought it was unjust.
All the evidence pointed to him,
but he was released without charge.
I still think Jin Isoo is the killer.
Gangha Violent Crime next arrested
a new suspect, Mr. Cho.
However, in just a day,
he was poisoned to death while in custody.
Finally, last night,
a new suspect, Mr. Hwang,
fell to his death
while fleeing from police.
Can we really call this a coincidence?
Some speculate that in an attempt
to divert suspicion from himself,
Detective Jin tried to frame Mr. Hwang,
who has no connection to this case,
as a new suspect.
Was his hand
reaching out to save him?
Or was it to push him?
-[TV beeps]
-[remote clatters]
She's spouting
whatever nonsense she wants.
She stepped in herself
as a former news anchor.
By the way,
how did Hwang Jongsu know?
It looked like he was running away.
How did he know that we suspected him?
Team 1.
Effective immediately,
you are all suspended.
Joo Hyera, do you have something to say?
The suspect in Kim Younghwan's murder case
died while in custody,
a victim's dead body was delivered here,
and the suspect in that murder
committed suicide.
You deserve to be suspended, don't you?
Get lost, all of you!
Stay out of my sight!
Chief.
Just stand down for now.
-But--
-Hyera.
If you keep this up,
you could lose your job.
How will you catch
Yu Seongwon as a civilian?
Come in.
-[door closes]
-I don't think it's even been 10 minutes
since I told you to stay out of my sight.
I'm here to make your wish come true, sir.
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
-[hand thuds on table]
-[exhales softly]
I'll leave.
That's your wish, isn't it?
So leave Detective Joo,
Detective Park, and Detective Choi alone.
They're already done for.
There's going to be
a disciplinary hearing.
You can all leave hand in hand.
What exactly did we do wrong?
If anyone did anything wrong here,
it wasn't us.
It was you, sir.
When we went,
Hwang Jongsu was already on the run.
As if he had already been warned.
I checked at the security office.
GANGHA POLICE STATION SECURITY OFFICE
Who did you call?
It was just a work call.
[Isoo] Sir.
Do you know who Hwang Jongsu is?
He's Yu Seongwon's closest associate.
He's protected Yu Seongwon
since Seongwon was a child.
If we're right and Yu Seongwon
committed murder in his studio,
Hwang Jongsu is both a witness
to everything and an accomplice.
Now do you understand what you did?
You leaked confidential information.
If you touch my team,
I'm going to expose it.
-[sighs]
Detective Joo.
What do we do now?
You'll be fine.
I'll find a way to stop it.
Hey, you're a detective.
This can happen while working a case.
No, that's not what I meant.
How do we catch Yu Seongwon?
The suspect's dead, and we're suspended.
Yu Seongwon won't stop.
What if he kills someone again?
-[sighs wearily]
-[door opens]
Why is everyone so down, huh?
What's this? You're clocking out already?
Unpack and get back to work.
I'm the only one leaving.
-What?
What are you talking about?
I made a deal with the police chief.
I'm the one he hates most.
I'll leave,
and you three won't be suspended.
[sighs] Jin Isoo.
You guys don't have anywhere to go.
I've got plenty of other options.
Bro.
-Are you really going to quit?
-Yes.
I just went ahead
and handed the chief my resignation.
[Junyoung] Hey.
What do you think you're doing?
This case started because of me.
The press will come after me, too.
Staying will only make it harder.
I'll clear this up later.
Take care. I'm a free man now.
-[door closes]
-[sighs softly]
Jin Isoo.
I'm sorry.
Why do you look so defeated?
I'll go out and do what I can
on the outside.
You should
hold things down here.
I'm not giving up on Yu Seongwon.
I'll catch him no matter what.
Mr. Jin Isoo is here.
Hello!
Are you here to complain?
No, I came to thank you.
I'm a civilian now, thanks to you.
I quit being a cop.
You even went on the air
to give a special broadcast,
and I got absolutely roasted.
So I thought I'd bring you a gift.
Here.
Go on, open it.
I went to all this trouble.
It's custom-made.
Is this gold?
Yes.
One for you, one for Seongwon.
If you ever want to turn yourself in,
wear that to Gangha Police Station.
[sighs] Chairman Jin Myeongchul
was a good man,
but his son's a letdown.
You should worry about your own son.
How did you bring him up to be a murderer?
Nothing's holding me back now.
Being a detective
comes with a lot of restrictions.
I need to play by the rules
and keep the brass happy.
I don't have that anymore.
Just watch and see how far I can go.
Are you busy, Mr. Chairman?
What brings you here?
You were eating.
Are you here because of the broadcast?
I filed a correction
with the arbitration commission.
They won't listen.
What?
Chairwoman Jeong Taeseon
was just using me.
Why?
-Because her son is a killer...
-[gasps]
...and I'm going to catch him.
What are you talking about?
The artist Yu Seongwon is a killer?
Yes, a serial killer.
So I got fired today.
What?
I'm unemployed.
I did give in my resignation,
but I was basically fired.
Then what are you going to do?
[Isoo] Mmm...
Mr. Choi.
Don't we have some white hackers here?
We don't have any on staff,
but we have people under contract.
Set me up with them.
I'm going to arrest
Yu Seongwon and Jeong Taeseon both.
All right. I'll give them a call.
Ah.
Our subsidiaries advertise on UBS, right?
Cancel everything.
I'm going to sue for defamation.
-Is that sushi?
-What? Oh.
-[chuckles]
-[sighs contentedly]
Mmm!
Detective Jin Isoo!
-I'm a fan.
-Right.
Really?
Yes.
Did you really kill Kim Younghwan?
No.
Oh, if you did, that'd be a killer story.
Can you stop talking about killing?
I heard you had a request for us.
Yes.
Find this person for me.
I think he's a close associate
of UBS's Jeong Taeseon.
He could be a former employee.
I can't find him in the company records.
Did this guy kill Kim Younghwan?
No.
But he is a murderer.
He killed the guy
who killed Kim Younghwan.
-Oh!
-Oh! [chuckling]
Can you find him without a name?
-Of course!
But before that, can I get your autograph?
Me too.
[scoffs] Bring me a pen.
JIN ISOO
DIRECTOR KIM IS HERE
Hansu pulled all their advertising.
I know. I heard.
They're even threatening a lawsuit.
We should issue a correction.
No, just leave it.
Pardon?
I said leave it. I'll handle it!
Yes, ma'am.
RETURN II
YU SEONGWON'S SOLO EXHIBITION
[director] Mr. Yu, welcome.
Yes, hello.
You're as handsome as always.
Have you been well?
Yes. I hope you've been well, too.
I've been so busy
getting the exhibition ready.
Come this way. We've set up the pieces.
What do you think?
For this exhibition,
that is the main piece.
It needs to be the first thing
people see when they walk in.
So vivid,
it almost seems alive.
FULL BLOOM, LIFE YET TO BLOOM
You get what I mean?
[chuckles softly] Yes.
JEONG TAESEON
-[Taeseon] Come to the office right now.
-[line disconnects]
We're meeting too often lately.
I've got a plane ready,
so leave right now.
I can't cover for you any more than this.
If they look into Mr. Hwang,
everything will link back to you.
Then there's nothing I can do.
Just stay out until I clean everything up.
I'm asking you.
Please!
If you really want it, then beg me.
Okay, fine.
It was a joke.
Fine.
I'll leave.
Okay, find out when and where
UBS' private jet is leaving today.
-Okay.
-[keyboard key clacks]
-[rapid digital beeping]
In two hours. Business aviation terminal.
Hello?
Yu Seongwon is flying out in two hours.
Where is he going?
[Isoo] I don't know,
but he's flying on a private jet.
Just go arrest him.
What will you do?
Dr. Seo said Yu Seongwon
would have kept all the evidence.
I'll go to his studio to find them.
Get ready to move out.
-Yes, ma'am.
-[switch clicks]
-[light beeps]
ECSTASY
A BREATHLESS FALL
JO NAYEONG
YU SEONGWON'S MODEL
CHOI YEONGMIN
CLIMAX
LIGHT SCATTERED ACROSS THE UNIVERSE
[Isoo] What's with the pebbles
and why stick the reed in?
DISSOLUTION
THE SILENCE OF WHISPERING REEDS
KIM HEEJUN
YU SEONGWON'S JUNIOR
FULL BLOOM, LIFE YET TO BLOOM
JEONG MINJAE
FORMER DETECTIVE
-[siren blaring]
-[cell phone vibrating]
[Isoo] It's me.
I found Yu Seongwon's real studio.
All the evidence is here.
He found the evidence.
-[engine revving]
-[tires screeching]
Chief, I'm inside Yu Seongwon's studio.
There's a basement here.
I found the victims' belongings
and photographic evidence.
I'll send Forensics over, so wait there.
Yes, sir.
-[engine roaring]
-[siren approaching]
-[siren stops]
Are you here to say goodbye?
Or have you grown attached to me?
-[Hyera] Yu Seongwon.
-[handcuffs clicking]
For the murders
of Jo Nayeong, Choi Yeongmin,
Kim Heejun, and Jeong Minjae...
I am placing you under arrest.
You sound confident.
Is it for certain this time?
Are you really sure
you can catch me?
RESIDENT REGISTRATION CARD
JIN ISOO
WHAT I HAD DRAWN WASN'T A HAT
YOU ALWAYS HAVE TO EXPLAIN
EVERYTHING TO GROWN-UPS
We got him.
Okay.
I'll be there soon.
[Seongwon] After all,
you're my Little Prince.
Where is Isoo right now?
Did he go to my exhibition hall?
-[grunts]
-[clattering]
-[panting]
[Isoo] Ah!
I've been looking everywhere for you.
Here you are, making a dramatic entrance.
-[heavy thud]
-[glass shattering]
-[sharp whoosh]
-[Isoo exclaims]
-[clatters]
-[Isoo grunts]
-[heavy thud]
-[blunt thud]
-[high-pitched ringing]
-[hammer clangs]
-[exhales in relief]
Jin Isoo is here inside the studio.
Burn him with it.
FLEX X COP 2
EPISODE 13
WHAT FATE AWAITS ISOO?
[Hyera] Chief.
What about Jin Isoo?
You'll wake up, right?
I know you won't let this break you.
Jin Isoo is still alive.
When it's done, leave the country.
[Taeseon's assistant] The basement
was destroyed. We won't find any evidence.
He's on the move with Yu Seongwon.
We're following them.
[Hyera] Detective Park! Detective Choi!
Yu Seongwon's gone. He ditched the car.
There's no choice. I'll finish this.
Do you get it now?
This is the death you love so much.
[Isoo] Yu Seongwon!
You crazy bastard.
NUMBER 1 SAFETY!! NUMBER 1 PUBLIC ORDER!!
GANGHA POLICE STATION
Should I just disappear?
Should I make one final piece?
Translated by Hyesoo Lee